Hi, welcome to learn and master guitar session 2,
嗨，欢迎来到 learn and master guitar 第二节，
we're going to cover some very important concepts today,
我们今天要讲一些非常重要的概念，
that all guitars should know,
所有的吉他都应该知道，
we're going to learn how to read music,
我们将学习如何阅读音乐，
a very important skill for you to know,
这是一项非常重要的技能，
as a guitarist, to be able to get the most out of your playing,
对于吉他手来说，要想最大限度地发挥自己的演奏能力，
we're going to learn about the music staff,
我们将了解音乐的东西，
um what some of the names of the notes are,
音符的一些名字是什么，
the rhythms and rests,
节奏和休止符，
going about playing with tablature,
使用吉他谱演奏，
which is how you're going to see a lot of the guitar music that you're gonna work with,
你将看到的许多吉他音乐，
will have music notation at the top and tablature at the bottom,
在顶部使用音符，在底部使用吉他谱，
so we're gonna learn how to tie those two together
所以我们将学习如何将这两个结合在一起，
and then last we're going to learn about the notes on the first and second strings,
最后我们将学习第一弦和第二弦上的音符，
we're going to learn our first notes, first six notes.
我们将学习我们的前六个音符。
I look forward to it, let's go and get started.
我期待着它，让我们开始吧。
Okay, you're ready to learn how to read music,
好的，你准备好学习阅读音乐了吗，
so many people think reading music is just incredibly complicated,
很多人认为阅读音乐是非常复杂的，
no human could ever understand,
没有人能理解，
and certainly no adult could ever learn as an adult,
当然也没有成年人能学习，
you know usually you may learn it as a kid,
你通常可能还是个孩子的时候学习，
I've been working with people of all ages for years
我和各个年龄段的人一起工作了很多年，
and I have not found that to be true.
但我没有发现这是真的。
Adults can pick this up as easily as kids
成年人可以像孩子一样很容易地学会这个，
and I can explain it to you in just a couple of short minutes
我可以在短短几分钟内向你解释，
of how to read music,
如何阅读音乐，
ready, let's go ahead and start.
准备，让我们继续，开始。
Music is written on a music staff,
音乐写在乐谱（五线谱）上，
a music staff consists of five lines and four spaces,
乐谱由五个线和四个间组成，
music staff goes across from left to right,
乐谱从左到右，
just like if you're reading a book,
就像你在读一本书，
the music travels along like that,
音乐就是这样移动的，
think of it like a timeline,
把它想象成一条时间线，
you need to divide that timeline up into equal segments
你需要将时间线分成相等的部分，
and those are called measures,
这些被称为小节，
and you divide them by little bars called bar lines,
然后你用被称为小节线的线来划分它们，
when you get to the end of a song,
当你到达一首歌的结尾时，
you have a big thick bar,
你会看到一条很粗的线，
there that's your double bar line at the end,
这是结尾的双纵线，
means you're at the end of the song.
意思是你在这首歌的结尾。
Let's get back to those five lines and four spaces,
让我们回到那五个线和四个间，
that's going to be real important,
这才是真正重要的，
where the note is, on the staff,
在乐谱上音符在哪里，
whether it's low or high,
它是低还是高，
determines whether it's a high note or a low note.
决定了它是高音还是低音。
Okay, at the top of the part of the staff,
好的，在乐谱的顶部，
it's a real high note,
这是一个非常高的音符，
at the bottom part of the staff,
在乐谱的底部，
it's a low notes,
这是一个低音符，
as you're traveling up,
当你向上移动时，
you would be traveling up in pitch,
你会以音调向上移动，
da da da da da da up like that.
da da da da da da ，像这样。
Let's talk about the lines,
我们来谈谈线，
we're going to learn the notes on the lines,
我们将学习线上的音符，
like I said in the first session,
就像我在第一节课上说的，
the musical alphabet goes from A to G
音乐字母从 A 到 G ，
and then it just starts repeating,
然后开始重复，
so I can't tell you to play an M or T or V or anything like that,
所以我不能告诉你演奏 M 或 T 或 V 或类似的东西，
but we can go from A to G and just keep repeating.
但我们可以从 A 到 G ，然后继续重复。
On the first line of our staff,
在乐谱的第 1 线，
there's five lines on that bottom line, that's the 1st line,
这里有五个线，最下面的线是第 1 线，
if the note is on there, it's an E,
如果音符在那里，这是 E ，
if it's on the 2nd line, it's a G,
如果是第 2 线，这是个 G ，
the 3rd line is a B,
第 3 线是 B ，
the 4th line is a D,
第 4 线是 D ，
and the 5th line is an F,
第 5 线是 F ，
E G B D F,
E G B D F ，
wait a minute, don't get confused,
等一下，别搞混了，
sounds an awful like, awful lot like the names of our strings,
听起来很像琴弦的名字，
two completely different concepts,
两个完全不同的概念，
use some of the same notes,
用了一些相同的音符，
but two different, two completely different concepts,
但是两个完全不同的概念，
so don't get confused,
所以不要混淆，
the notes on the lines are E G B D and F,
线上的音符是 E G B D F ，
well, just as letter names, they're kind of hard to remember,
只是字母的名字，它们很难记住，
so how everybody remembers them is,
所以每个人记住它们的方式是，
every good boy does fine,
每个好孩子都做得很好，
corresponding to the E G B D F,
与 E G B D F 相对应，
every good boy does fine.
每个好孩子都做得很好。
Okay, let's practice, see how well you remember,
让我们练习一下，看看你记得有多清楚，
if the note is here, what is it,
如果音符在这里，它是什么，
good, what about if it's here,
很好，如果它在这里呢，
and what about here.
那这里呢。
Learning the notes is very important,
学习音符是非常重要的，
we've learned the notes on the lines,
我们已经学习了每一行上的音符，
every good boy does fine,
每个好孩子都能做得很好，
kind of rhymes with line,
与线一致，
it's a good way to remember it,
这是一个很好的记住它的方法，
now we're talking about the notes that are on the spaces,
现在我们谈论的是在这些间上的音符，
in between those lines,
在那些线之间，
the note can also be on those spaces,
音符也可以在那些间上，
there's only four of those,
它们只有四个，
so counting up from the bottom,
所以从底部开始计数，
the first one of those, the first space, that note is an F,
第一个间的音符是 F ，
the second space an A,
第二个间是 A ，
the third space a C,
第三个间是 C ，
the fourth space an E,
第四个间是 E ，
F A C and E,
F A C E ，
which conveniently spells the word face,
它很方便地拼写成单词 face ，
which kind of rhymes with space,
它与间一致，
so that's a good way to remember, to keep track of both of them.
所以这是一个记住它们的好方法。
So let's practice the space,
所以让我们练习间，
the notes on the spaces,
间上面的音符，
if the note is here, what is it,
如果音符在这里，它是什么，
and what about this one, what about if it's here,
那么这个呢，如果它在这里呢，
and lastly, what if it's here, what note is that.
最后，如果它在这里呢，这是什么音符。
Great, now let's mix it up a little bit,
很好，现在让我们把它混合起来，
we're going to mix up between lines and spaces,
我们将线和间混合，
give you a little practice on that.
给你们一些练习。
So if the note is here, what would that be,
所以，如果音符在这里，它是什么，
now let's switch over, what if it's here, what would that be,
现在我们切换一下，如果它在这里呢，它是什么，
what about this one,
这个呢，
is that on a line or a space,
它是在线上还是间上，
that you need to ask yourself
你需要问自己，
and then you put in the right phrase that goes with that,
然后你说出与之相配的正确短语，
what about this one,
那么这个呢，
and lastly, what about this one.
最后，这个呢。
Pretty good, got a handle on those,
很好，了解了这些，
now the notes can also be above or below the staff as well,
音符也可以在五线谱的上方或下方，
so they can be in between,
所以它们可以介于，
we've learned the notes that are on those five lines and on those four spaces,
我们知道音符在五条线和四个间上，
but they can also be higher than that,
但它们也可以高于那个，
what if I want to play a note that's higher than that,
如果我想演奏一个高于那个的音符，
how does that work,
这是如何起作用的，
well, you can do that,
你可以做到这一点，
that's no problem at all,
完全没有问题，
let's count up,
让我们往上数，
let's go up first,
让我们先往上，
so let's start,
所以让我们开始，
here's a D, 4th line,
这是 D 在 4 线上，
and then let's go up one,
然后让我们向上一个，
what would this one be,
这个是什么，
well, that would be an E, that's that top space,
那应该是 E ，那是最上面的间，
if we go up one more, we're on that top line, that would be an F,
如果我们再往上一个，我们在最上面的线上，那是 F ，
now if I want to go higher than that,
如果我想再高一点，
I put my note up on top of that top staff
我把我的音符放在最高的线的上面，
and what do you think that one would be,
你觉得那会是什么，
well, let's figure it out,
好的，让我们想办法，
D E F, the next one would be G,
D E F ，下一个是 G ，
now, if I need to go up higher than that,
现在，如果我需要更高，
that's no problem at all,
这完全没有问题，
although I cant just have my note hanging up here in space,
虽然我不能把我的音符放在间上，
I have to add a line to it,
我必须在上面加一条线，
so you kind of have a reference point of where it is in relationship to the other lines,
所以你可以有一个参照点，它与其他线的关系，
that little line is called a ledger line,
这条线被称为加线，
and it's very important.
这是非常重要的。
Now let's go down,
现在让我们往下走，
let's go the other way,
让我们从另一个方向走，
we're going to start on, let's start on a G,
让我们从 G 开始，
on that line,
在那条线上，
now we're gonna go down one more,
现在我们下去一个，
this is the 1st space, that would be an F,
这是一间，它是 F ，
now we're down to the first line, E,
现在我们到第一线， E ，
now, if I go one more underneath that,
现在，如果我再往下走一步，
what do you think that one would be,
你认为这会是什么呢，
now we're going in reverse,
现在我们倒过来，
it's a little bit tricky here,
这有点棘手，
G F E, this one would be a D,
G F E ，这个应该是 D ，
and if I need to go down a little bit further,
如果我需要再往下走一点，
if I go down one more,
如果我再往下走一条，
of course I have to add my ledger line there,
我必须在那里加上我的加线，
this would be a C, now we're going down backwards in the in the staff.
这应该是 C ，现在我们要回退了。
Okay, so there's the names of notes,
好的，这是音符的名字，
that's on the line, every good boy does fine,
在线上，每个好孩子都会做得很好，
if it's on a space, F A C E,
如果它在间上， F A C E ，
if it's above or below,
如果它在以上或以下，
you just have to count them up and add it from there,
你需要把它们加起来，然后从那里加起来，
now let's learn about rhythm.
现在让我们来学习节奏。
Alright, let's talk about rhythm now,
好的，现在我们来讨论节奏，
rhythm, it tells us how long the notes are,
节奏告诉我们音符有多长，
notes come in different lengths,
音符有不同的长度，
we're talking about the length of the notes now,
我们现在讨论音符的长度，
you're still with me,
你还在听，
I haven't bored you too much now on the music reading into things,
我没有让你在音乐阅读方面太无聊，
let's go for rhythm just for a couple of minutes
让我们去做几分钟的节奏，
and then we'll get into some guitar playing,
然后我们会弹一些吉他，
the first note we need to learn about is the whole note,
我们需要学习的第一个音符是全音符，
that would be an open circle, nothing inside, no stem or anything
是一个开放的圆圈，里面什么也没有，没有符杆，
and that gets four beats,
有四个节拍，
whole notes get four beats,
全音符有四个节拍，
I wish there was a good way,
我希望有一个好的方法，
you could do this other than memorizing it,
你可以更好的记住它，
but I don't know, you just need to memorize it,
但是你只需要记住它，
whole notes get four beats,
全音符有四个节拍，
that would be four,
它是四个，
so if I'm counting,
如果我数的话，
it would be one two three four,
它是一二三四，
that would be a whole note,
这是一个全音符，
if I was playing it,
如果我弹奏它，
it would be something like this, one two three four,
它会像这样，一二三四，
that would be a whole note.
那是一个全音符。
A half note is an open circle and it has a stem on it,
二分音符是一个开放的圆圈，上面有一个符干，
now the stem will point either direction, either up or down,
符干会指向任何一个方向，向上或向下，
it doesn't matter which way the stem points,
无论符干指向哪个方向，
the stem can point up or down,
符干可以向上或向下，
what matters is that it has a stem,
重要的是它有一个符干，
it has a stem, it's an open circle, it's a half note
它有一个符干，是一个开放的圆圈，它是一个二分音符，
and half notes, get two beats.
二分音符有两个节拍。
So we've talked about whole notes get four,
所以我们已经讨论了全音符有四个，
half notes get two.
二分音符有两个。
Okay, let's talk about two more,
好的，让我们再讨论两个，
if it's a filled in circle and has a stem,
如果它是一个填充的圆圈和一个符干，
blackened out circles and a stem,
黑色的圆圈和符干，
that's what's called a quarter note
这就是四分音符，
and he gets one beat,
它有一个节拍，
think of it like a whole dollar,
把它想象成一个美元，
a whole note is filled with four quarters,
一个全音符填满四个四分音符，
Four quarter notes, quarter note gets one beat,
四分音符是一个节拍，
so it takes four them to fill up a whole Dollar,
所以需要四个它们填充一个美元，
half notes get two beats,
二分音符有两个节拍，
it takes two of them to make up a whole note.
需要两个组成一个全音符。
Now the last one we're going to talk about is an eighth note,
现在我们要讨论的最后一个是八分音符，
he gets a half a beat,
它得到半拍，
so it takes two eighth notes to make up one quarter note,
所以需要两个八分音符才能组成一个四分音符，
two quarter notes to make up one half note,
两个四分音符组成一个二分音符，
two half notes to make up one whole note.
两个二分音符组成一个全音符。
Don't get lost in all that,
不要迷失在所有这些东西中，
just a couple things you need to remember,
你只需要记住几件事，
whole notes get four,
全音符有四个（节拍），
half notes get two,
二分音符有两个（节拍），
quarter notes get one,
四分音符有一个（节拍），
and eighth notes get a half a beat,
八分音符有半个节拍，
we'll learn more about eighth in a coming session,
我们将在接下来的课程中学习更多关于八分音符的知识，
we won't deal with eighth too much right now.
我们现在不会太多地讨论八分音符。
Now let's talk about the measures,
现在让我们来谈谈小节，
inside of those measures,
在这些小节之中，
we have to have sound and silence,
我们有声音和静音，
sound is represented by the notes,
声音是由音符代表的，
now we're going to talk about,
现在我们要讲，
how do I want to note it,
我怎么记它，
if I want silence in there,
如果我想要静音，
we're going to talk about rests,
我们将讨论休止符，
with each one of the notes, that we just went through,
对于我们刚刚说到的每个音符，
there's a corresponding rest that goes with it as well,
都有一个相应的休止符，
it's just a little symbol,
它只是一个小符号，
that represents not playing for a certain amount of time,
代表在一定时间内不演奏，
the first one we're going to cover is a whole rest,
我们要介绍的第一个是全休止符，
which looks like a dash that hangs down from the line,
它看起来像从线上垂下来的破折号，
whole rest gets four beat, just like a whole note gets four beats.
全休止符是四拍，就像一个全音符有四拍。
The next one is a half rest,
下一个是二分休止符，
a half rest gets two beats, just like a half note gets two beats,
二分休止符有两个节拍，就像二分音符有两个节拍一样，
now half rest, be careful is a dash that sticks up from the line,
二分休止符，注意，是一个从线上突出的破折号，
just to confuse you,
让你困惑的是，
there just almost look exactly the same,
它们看起来几乎完全一样，
how does everybody tell the difference,
人们如何区分，
well, the whole note has more beats in it, so it's heavier,
好的，全音符有更多的节拍，所以它更重，
so it hangs down from the line,
所以它从线上垂下来，
that's where everybody remembers it,
这就是每个人记住它的地方，
that's how I got the music school remembering it.
这就是我让音乐学校记住它的方式。
So, you've got whole notes, whole rest, half notes, half rest,
所以，你有了全音符，全休止符，二分音符，二分休止符，
next one is a quarter rest,
然后是四分休止符，
quarter rest kind of looks like an upside-down lightning bolt looking thing,
四分休止符看起来有点像倒立的闪电，
that's a quarter rest
这是四分休止符，
and he's good for one beat,
他适合一个节拍，
so I want you to play for one beat, I give you a quarter note,
所以我要你演奏一个节拍，我给你一个四分音符，
quarter rest, for if I want you to be quiet for one beat or be silent for one beat.
四分休止符，如果我想让你静音一拍。
Last one is an eighth rest,
最后一个是八分休止符，
an eighth rest kind of looks like backwards italicized seven,
八分休止符看起来像一个倒置的斜体 7 ，
that's a symbol for that,
那是一个符号，
that's an eighth rest
那是八分休止符，
and that would mean that you are silent for half a beat.
那意味着你静音半拍。
Got it?
明白了吗？
Whole rests, whole notes, four beats,
全休止符，全音符，四个节拍，
half rest, half note, two beats,
二分休止符，二分音符，两个节拍，
quarter rests and notes, one beat,
四分休止符，四分音符，一个节拍，
eighth rest and notes a half a beat.
八分休止符，八分音符，半拍。
Only two more musical concepts, I need to teach you,
只有两个音乐概念，我需要教给你，
before we often run and learn in our first notes.
在我们运行和学习第一个音符之前。
First one is the treble clef,
第一个是高音谱号，
this cursive S looking thing,
这个草书 S 样子的东西，
you'll see at the beginning of every piece of music,
你会在每一段音乐的开头看到，
every line of piece of music that you'll be playing,
你要演奏的每一行音乐，
all that is telling you is that,
所有要告诉你的是，
the music you're about to see is
即将看到的音乐是
written for guitar or flute or trumpet, a clarinet anything like that,
为吉他或笛子或小号或单簧管之类的乐器写的，
that's a high in pitch, that's a treble clef,
那是一个高音，那是一个高音谱号，
make sure that is on the front of every piece of music that you play
确保它在你演奏的每一首音乐的前面，
and generally it will be you won't need to worry about it.
通常你不需要担心它。
Next one is going to be the time signature,
下一个是拍号，
right after the clef,
就在谱号后面，
you're going to see the time signature, it's two numbers on top of each other,
你会看到拍号是两个数字叠加在一起，
most of the time, it will be a four and a four
大多数时候是 4 和 4 ，
and that's just telling you exactly how many beats are going to be in each measure,
这只是告诉你每个小节有多少个节拍，
the top number is the one, that's important,
上面的数字是重要的，
tells you how many beats are going to be each measure,
告诉你每节有多少个节拍，
think of it as a timeline,
把它想象成一个时间线，
they have to divide it up into equal segments,
他们把它分成相等的部分，
the time signature tells us what it tells you what they are.
拍号告诉我们它们是什么。
Now the most common time signature that we play in here in the western world is four beats per measure,
现在，在西方世界，我们演奏的最常见的拍号是每小节四个节拍，
you'll see a four and a four on top of it.
你会看到四和四在上面。
Okay, it's so common, folks just call it common time,
好的，它很普通，人们叫它普通拍子，
sometimes they even abbreviate the term common time to just be a C,
有时他们甚至把普通拍子缩写为 C ，
so sometimes you'll see after that treble clef,
所以有时你会看到高音谱号后面看到，
sometimes you'll see a four four,
有时你会看到 4/4 ，
sometimes you'll just see a C,
有时你会看到 C ，
all that means the same thing to you,
对你来说都是一样的意思，
four beats per measure.
每一小节四个节拍。
Alright, enough of all that music stuff,
好了，音乐的内容说够了，
let's get down to playing a little bit.
让我们开始演奏吧。
All right, at last we're down to playing,
好的，最后我们开始演奏，
now we're finally getting to the good stuff,
我们终于开始演奏东西了，
we're going to talk about the notes on the first string, that E string,
我们要讨论第一弦上的音符， E 弦，
there's three notes on that E string,
E 弦上有三个音符，
okay, that we're going to learn today, E F and G,
好的，我们今天要学到的， E F G ，
here's how they look in music notation,
这是它们在乐谱中的样子，
when you see the E that top space,
当你看到那个顶部的间，
that's not just any, that's first string open,
这不是任何，这是空的第一弦，
which should be like this, that would b E,
就像这样，这是 E ，
if I put my first finger on the first fret, still that first string,
如果我把食指放在第一品上面，仍然是第一弦，
and play that, that's F,
演奏这个，这是 F ，
which is the top line on your music staff,
这是你的乐谱的最上面的线，
every good boy does fine,
每个好孩子都做得很好，
So we've got E, we've got F.
所以我们有 E ，我们有 F 。
And the third one is G,
第三个是 G ，
we come up to our third finger on the third fret, that's a G.
我们使用无名指在三品上面，这是 G 。
So let's play it together,
所以让我们一起演奏，
E F G,
E F G ，
one more time,
再来一次，
E F,
E F ，
good down strokes with our pick,
用我们的拨片拨动，
we're bracing with our hand,
用我们的手支撑，
G, hold it out, keep that pressure on it nice and long.
G ，保持一下，保持这种压力。
Good, E F and G,
好的， E F 和 G ，
those are the notes that we're going to learn on the first string,
这些是我们要在第一弦上学习的音符，
now let's do the first exercise that's in your book.
现在让我们做你的书中的第一个练习。
You'll notice, we're dealing with whole notes,
你会注意到，我们处理的是全音符，
how many beats do whole notes get,
全音符有多少拍，
whole notes get four beats.
全音符有四拍。
Okay, now as you're looking at that exercise,
好的，现在你在看练习的时候，
you've got the music notation at the top,
你在上面有乐谱，
you've also got your tablature notation at the bottom,
你在下面有吉他谱，
that tells you where to put your fingers
告诉你把手指放在哪里，
or which strings are being played rather and where to fret the notes,
或者演奏哪个弦，以及在哪个品演奏音符，
okay so you get a little bit of both,
好的，所以你得到了两个，
you get the music notation and the other
你得到了乐谱和其他的，
and I would suggest that you go ahead
我建议你继续，
and write in above those notes, the names of the notes,
在这些音符的上方写上音符的名字，
because you'll learn all kinds of stuff,
因为你将学习各种各样的东西，
now you'll learn how to read music and play the notes
你将学习如何阅读音乐和演奏音符，
and where they're out on the guitar,
以及它们在吉他上的位置，
go ahead and write in the notes, above those pitches for that first exercise,
继续在第一个练习的音符上写下音符，
I've got the first couple written in for you,
我已经为你写下了第一对，
go ahead and take a second and write those in.
继续，花一点时间，把它们写进去。
Okay, got it written in?
好的，写好了吗？
Here we go, let's play,
我们开始吧，我们来弹奏，
let me, I'll play the first couple of bars where you can kind of see how this goes,
我将演奏前几个小节，你们可以看到是怎么回事，
we're picking with her, right hand over here,
我们拿着它，右手在这里，
we've got an E, which is open,
我们有一个空的 E ，
on the first string as the first note,
在第一弦第一个音符，
so it would be like this,
就像这样，
ready play, two, I hold it for four beats, three four,
准备，弹奏， 2 ，我持续四个节拍， 3 4 ，
and F two three four,
F 2 3 4 ，
and G two three four,
G 2 3 4 ，
then back to F, two three,
然后回到 F 2 3 ，
open E now two,
现在空弦 E ， 2 ，
third finger G, two three four
无名指 G ， 2 3 4 ，
and last one E two three four
最后一个 E ， 2 3 4 ，
and you've got a double line,
你得到了一条双纵线，
that means we're stopped.
这意味着我们停止。
Right now let's try and play that one together,
现在，让我们试着一起演奏这一条，
you're ready,
你准备好了，
let's try it together,
让我们一起试一试，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
E two three four,
E 2 3 4 ，
now f make sure your fingering good,
现在 F ，确保你的指法是好的，
now here comes a G two three four,
现在是 G ， 2 3 4 ，
F, keep that finger pressure on all the way through that,
F ，一直按住手指，一直到那个，
here comes the E, two three four,
现在是 E ， 2 3 4 ，
G, two three four,
G 2 3 4 ，
E two three four.
E 2 3 4 。
Very good, you're reading music,
很好，你在读音乐，
you're playing your guitar,
你在弹吉他，
let's go to exercise number two.
我们来做第二个练习。
Now we get into half notes,
现在我们进入二分音符，
remember half notes get two beats,
记得二分音符有两个节拍，
so we're going slightly quicker on this one,
所以我们现在稍微快一点，
let's play it together,
让我们一起演奏，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
E, one, two,
E ， 1 2 ，
now comes in F, one two,
现在进入 F ， 1 2 ，
back to E, one two,
回到 E ， 1 2 ，
G,
G ，
back to F,
回到 F ，
back to F, one two,
回到 F ， 1 2 ，
E, two.
E ， 2 。
Very good, now let's go to the next one, exercise three,
好的，现在我们来做下一个练习，练习三，
exercise exercise three excuse me has quarter notes,
练习三有四分音符，
now we're getting even faster,
现在我们变得更快了，
whole notes get four beats,
全音符有四个节拍，
half notes get two beats,
二分音符有两个节拍，
quarter note gets one beat,
四分音符有一个节拍，
here we go,
开始，
let's play exercise number three together.
让我们一起演奏练习三。
Ready, starts on that E,
准备，从 E 开始，
bracing our hand, got good hand position here,
支撑我们的手，在这里得到了很好的手的位置，
our hands nice and open on our left hand,
我们的左手张开，
ready, start,
准备，开始，
E E, now F, G,
E E ，现在 F G ，
here comes a half note,
这有一个二分音符，
one, two, one two,
1 2 ， 1 2 ，
one two three four.
1 2 3 4 。
Let's talk about how do you stop a note,
让我们来讨论一下如果停止一个音符，
if you've got an open string like this
如果你有一个像这样的空弦，
and I want to stop it,
我想停下来，
well, how do I stop it from ringing,
我怎么才能让它停止响动，
well, I stop at a couple different ways,
我用几种不同的方式停止，
if I put my palm down on this end,
如果我把我的手掌放在这一端，
I can stop it there
我可以把它停在那里，
or I can also just touch the strings with my left hand
或者我也可以用我的左手触摸弦，
and that stops it there,
就在那里停下来，
if I'm playing, let's say G
如果我在演奏，比如说 G ，
and I'm fretting the note,
我在拨动音符，
well how do I stop that note,
我如何停止那个音符，
I can just let off the pressure
我可以只是释放压力，
and it stops,
它就停止了，
I don't need to necessarily even take my finger off the guitar,
我不需要把我的手指从吉他上移开，
I just need to let off the pressure and it comes up.
我只需要释放压力，它就会出现。
Let's do the last one, exercise four.
让我们做最后一个，练习四。
Here, ready,
准备开始，
starts on a G this time,
这次在 G 上开始，
third finger first string,
无名指第一弦，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
one two,
1 2 ，
down to E, one, two,
降到 E ， 1 2 ，
F, one two,
F ， 1 2 ，
E,
E ，
now G, go, one, two.
现在 G ，开始， 1 2 。
Very good, okay, let's talk about the notes on the second string,
很好，让我们来讨论一下第二弦上的音符，
the first string, we had E F and G,
第一弦上我们有 E F G ，
now on the second string, we're going to learn three notes as well,
在第二弦上，我们也会学习三个音符，
on the second string, that B string,
在第二弦上， B 弦，
if you play it open, that's gonna be B,
如果你弹空弦，就会是 B ，
the third line up,
在第三线上，
now on the second string with the first finger,
现在在第二弦上，用食指，
this one's gonna be called C,
这个是 C ，
now third finger on that second string is a D,
现在无名指在第二弦上，是 D ，
so we have B,
所以我们有 B ，
let's play it together,
让我们一起演奏，
C, first finger,
C ，食指，
third finger, D.
无名指 D 。
Great, let's take a look at that first exercise,
好的，让我们来看看第一个练习，
it involves whole notes
它涉及到全音符，
and whole notes get what, whole notes get four beats.
全音符得到什么，全音符得到四个节拍。
Let's play this together,
让我们一起弹奏，
ready starting on that B,
从 B 开始，
ready play,
准备，弹奏，
two three four,
2 3 4 ，
C, two three four,
C ， 2 3 4 ，
D, two three four,
D ， 2 3 4 ，
B, two three,
B ， 2 3 ，
back to D now, two three four,
现在回到 D ， 2 3 4 ，
B, two three four
B ，2 3 4 ，
and lastly C two three four.
最后， C ， 2 3 4 。
Everybody got it,
大家都明白了吗，
okay, now I'm going to skip down,
好的，现在我们跳过，
since we've already spent a lot of time on it,
因为我们已经花了很多时间了，
let's skip the half note exercise,
我们跳过二分音符的练习，
I want you to do that on your own,
我希望你们自己做，
but just for the sake of time,
但为了节省时间，
let's move on to number three.
让我们跳到第三个。
This involves quarter notes,
这涉及到四分音符，
let's play this one,
让我们弹奏这个，
starts on that B again,
再次从 B 开始，
nice and slow and steady,
慢一点，稳一点，
here we go.
我们开始。
Ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
B, another B,
B ，另一个 B ，
first finger, C,
食指， C ，
there you go, D, one two,
继续， D ， 1 2 ，
[] measure, B C D,
[]小节， B C D ，
and two three four,
2 3 4 ，
very good.
很好。
Now there's the fourth exercise there too,
现在还有第四个练习，
I'll leave you to do that on your own,
我会让你自己做，
main thing as you're playing,
在你演奏的时候，
you want to make sure you're having good hand position on your left hand,
你想确保你的左手有好的位置，
good hand position on your right hand
你的右手有好的位置，
and that you're playing nice and steady,
你弹奏得又好又稳，
I don't care about speed at this point,
现在我不关心速度，
as much as I do steadiness,
我关心的是稳定性，
that you're able to change between the notes at the proper time without hesitating or anything like that.
你可以在适当的时间毫不犹豫地在音符之间切换。
Now let's get to playing notes on both the first and the second strings,
现在让我们开始演奏第一弦和第二弦的音符，
okay, now we're going to talk about all the notes that we've learned so far,
好的，现在我们将讨论到目前为止我们学到的所有音符，
let's review, on the first string, we've got E F and G,
让我们复习一下，在第一弦上，我们有 E F G ，
E, first finger F, third finger G,
E ，食指 F ，无名指 G ，
on the second string,
在第二弦上，
now we've got open B, first finger C, third finger D,
我们有空弦 B ，食指 C ，无名指 D ，
so not only are we worried about playing these,
所以我们不仅担心演奏它们，
we also worried about reading them,
我们还担心阅读它们，
I would encourage you to go back and write in the notes,
我建议你们回去，写下音符，
if you're having trouble remembering what's a D, what's a C,
如果你们记不清 D 是什么， C 是什么，
write those notes in above the exercises,
把那些音符写在练习上面，
at this stage of the game,
在游戏的这个阶段，
you need all the help you can get in these exercises,
你们需要这些练习中的所有帮助，
we've included a bunch of exercises,
我们有一系列的练习，
for each of the set, for each of the strings,
对于每根弦，
you have more exercises for the first string,
你有更多的第一弦练习，
more exercises for the second string
更多的第二弦练习，
and more exercises for both of these strings together,
还有更多的这两根弦的练习，
I would encourage you to play through all these exercises,
我会鼓励你一起演奏这些练习，
you need every bit of help going through these exercises,
你需要的练习的每一点帮助，
that is going to pay off,
都会有回报的，
when we get more and more strings and more and more notes involved,
当我们得到越来越多的琴弦和越来越多的音符时，
you're gonna, you're gonna really thank yourself,
你会真的感谢自己，
that you went through these exercises,
你经历了这些练习，
so don't just go through them once and conquer them.
所以不要只经历一次就征服它们。
Go through them
练习一遍，
and then when you come back again the next day go through them again,
第二天回来的时候再练习一遍，
you'll find you'll be able to do them faster and faster and faster,
你会发现你可以越来越快地完成它们，
and that's where we're going.
这就是我们要做的。
Let's talk about doing the first and second string,
我们来讨论一下第一弦和第二弦，
I'm mixing and combining all of the notes,
我把所有音符混合在一起，
you're ready, we're going to exercise number one.
你准备好了，我们要做第一个练习。
Starts on that first string, open E,
从第一弦，空弦 E 开始，
we'll take it easy, this first time through,
我们第一次会慢一点，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
E,
E ，
now to an F,
现在是 F ，
here comes a G, one two,
这里是 G ，1 2 ，
now it comes to B, second string,
现在是 B ，第二弦，
first finger C,
食指 C ，
D C B, comes a C,
D C B ，一个 C ，
half notes here, half note here,
这里是二分音符，这里是二分音符，
here comes to C, hang onto it for, for four beats and stop.
这是 C ，维持它四个节拍，然后停止。
Very good, let's go to the next one, exercise number two,
很好，我们来做下一个，练习二，
we'll go a little bit faster on this one.
这次我们会更快一点。
Ready play,,
准备，开始，
one two.
1 2 。
Very good, I know we kind of kicked it up a notch on that one,
很好，我知道我们在这一点上提升了一个档次，
try your best to keep up,
尽你最大的努力跟上，
you can always go back and review,
你可以随时回去复习，
let's skip down to number four,
让我们跳到第四，
do number three, when you practice by yourself,
当你自己练习的时候，做练习三，
we'll also do it in workshop time,
我们也会在 workshop 时间做，
but let's do it number four right now.
但我们现在做练习四
This takes you through all the notes ascending and descending,
这将带你通过所有音符，升序和降序，
that's why I wanted to cover this one.
这就是为什么我想要介绍这个。
Ready play,
准备，演奏，
number four,
第四个，
one two, then backup to G,
1 2 ，回到 G ，
very good.
很好。
Alright, let's talk about your assignment,
好的，让我们来谈谈你的作业，
for this session two, this is our assignment.
对于第二节课，这是我们的作业。
What you need to do for me is the note reading exercises in the book,
你需要做的是书中的音符阅读练习，
do as many of them as you can, the more practice you get the better.
尽可能多地做，练习越多越好。
Do the first string exercises, there's also more for string exercises,
做第一弦练习，还有更多的弦练习，
there's second string exercises and more second string exercises
还有第二弦练习和更多的第二弦练习，
and then you have both strings together, first and second string,
然后你把第一弦和第二弦放在一起，
do all of those exercises.
做所有这些练习。
Also, there's two songs I'm giving you,
还有，有两首我要给你的歌，
Ode to Joy is the first one
Ode to Joy 是第一首，
and the second one is Jingle Bells,
第二首是 Jingle Bells ，
make sure you can play through both of those at this point,
确保你能弹完这两首歌，
I know it's not quite the most exciting music at this point,
我知道这不是令人兴奋的音乐，
but hey you only know six notes,
但是，你只知道六个音符，
so there's only so much we can do,
所以我们只能做这么多了，
anyway, we'll see you next time.
无论如何，我们下次再见。
Alright, welcome to the workshop time,
好的，欢迎来到 workshop 时间，
let's go ahead and get to work,
让我们开始工作，
we've got a lot of notes that we've learned
我们已经学到了很多音符，
and a lot of strings that we've covered,
学到了很多弦，
so let's go ahead and go through some of these exercises,
所以让我们继续学习一些练习，
the first exercise that I'm going to pull from are going to be the more exercises,
我要做的第一个练习是，更多练习，
the first one we're gonna look at is the more first string exercises.
第一个练习是更多第一弦练习。
Okay, let's look at number one of that,
好的，让我们来看看其中的第一个，
starts on that E, good hand position,
从 E 开始，好的手的位置，
open E,
空弦 E ，
if you need to write in the notes,
如果你需要写音符，
try writing the notes before we get started,
试着在我们开始之前写下音符，
come back to me.
再来找我。
Here we go, let's try it together,
开始，让我们一起试一试，
ready, play E one two,
准备，弹奏 E ， 1 2 ，
F,
F ，
G, two three four,.
G ，2 3 4
And here's the G, hold it out, hold it out, hold it out,
这是 G ，坚持住，
now you stop.
现在你停下来。
Number two,
第二个，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
one, two, very good.
1 2 ，非常好。
Number three,
第三个，
ready play,
准备，开始，
one two, one two, two three four.
1 2 ， 1 2 ， 2 3 4 。
Let's speed it up a little bit when we get to number four.
当我们到了第四个的时候，把速度加快一点。
Ready play,
准备，演奏，
one two three four,
1 2 3 4 ，
one, half note here,
1 ，这里的二分音符，
E two three four.
E 2 3 4 。
Very good, last one down here is five,
非常好，最后一个是第五个，
it's a two line exercise,
这是一个两行的练习，
so when you get to the end of that first line,
当你到达第一行的末尾，
jump down and immediately start reading the second line,
跳下来，立即开始阅读第二行，
here you go,
开始，
just a little bit longer than the others,
只是比其他稍微长一点，
we'll try it a little bit faster.
我们试着更快一点。
One two, ready go, one two,
1 2 ，开始，1 2 ，
jump down to that next line, play,
跳到下一行，演奏，
one two three four, very good.
1 2 3 4 ，非常好。
Okay, now we're gonna move on to more second string exercises,
好的，现在我们到更多的第二弦练习，
start with that first one,
从第一个开始，
starts on that B,
从 B 开始，
get your hand position, bracing your hand, open string,
手放好位置，支撑你的手，空弦，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
one two, one two, two three four,
1 2 ， 1 2 ， 2 3 4 ，
one two, one two, one two, one two three four.
1 2 ， 1 2 ， 1 2 ， 1 2 3 4 。二一二三四太二号了。
Great, number two,
好的，第二个，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
one two.
1 2 。
Now for number three, we'll go a little bit faster on this one.
现在第三个，我们会在这个更快一点。
Ready, go,
准备，开始，
one two, one two, two three four.
1 2 ， 1 2 ， 2 3 4 。
Number four,
第四个，
ready, play,
准备，演奏，
one two, two three four, two three four.
1 2 ， 2 3 4 ， 2 3 4 ，
Here comes number five, another two liner,
这是第五个，另一个两行，
let's kick it up a notch,
让我们把它上一个档次，
let's go a little bit faster,
让我们再快一点，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
next line, ready, go,
下一行，准备，开始，
one two, one two three four.
1 2 ， 1 2 3 4 。
Man, we're really cooking on that one,
我们真的在做那个，
now let's go to the both both string exercises,
现在让我们来做两个弦的练习，
so it's more first and second string exercises.
所以更多的第一弦和第二个弦练习。
Okay, now we're gonna do more first and second string exercises
好的，现在我们要做更多的第一弦和第二弦练习，
and go through these,
通过这些，
we're going to kick it up a little bit with the tempo
我们节奏稍微加快一点，
to make sure that you're getting it at the right speed,
确保你以正确的速度得到它，
let's start with number one.
让我们从第一个开始。
One two, ready go.
1 2 ，准备，开始。
Now, if you find that we're going too fast for you,
现在，如果你发现我们对你来说太快了，
as you practice these over the coming days,
在接下来的几天里，随着你练习这些，
you'll get quicker and quicker rhythm,
你会有越来越快的节奏，
so the more practice you get, the faster you'll get rhythm.
所以你练习得越多，你就会有更快的节奏。
Number two, now we include some of the rest there,
第二个，我们现在加入了一些休止符，
remember a quarter rest is one beat,
记得四分音符是一个节拍，
so you have to kind of count on this one,
所以你得数着这个，
we'll do a little bit slower,
我们会稍微慢一点，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
rest, rest, rest, rest.
静音，静音，静音，静音。
Very good, number three,
非常好，第三个，
right, this one, it has a half rest in,
这个有二分休止符，
half rest gets two beats,
二分休止符有两个节拍，
ready go,
准备，开始，
rest, rest, rest, rest, rest, one two.
静音，静音，静音，静音， 1 2 。
Well, let's do one more of these,
好的，让我们再做一个，
this will be number four,
这是第四个，
this one jumps around quite a bit,
这个跳跃了很多，
maybe a little tricky at first,
可能一开始有点棘手，
ready play,
准备，演奏，
rest, at rest is tricky there on that one,
静音，静音的那个很棘手，
go through I'll let you go through the rest of the exercises there on your own,
我会让你们自己完成剩下的练习，
because I really want to get to the song,
因为我很想说这首歌，
let's talk about Ode to Joy.
让我们谈谈 Ode to Joy 。
Okay, now for Ode to Joy,
好的，对于 Ode to Joy ，
we're combining all the elements that we've learned so far,
我们结合了我们目前学到的所有元素，
all of our notes
我们所有的音符，
and also we're going to throw in those chords too,
我们还会加入那些和弦，
let's work on those notes first,
让我们先弹这些音符，
Ode to Joy,
Ode to Joy ，
we'll go through its slow one time
我们第一次会慢一点，
and then we'll go through it fast.
然后我们会快一点。
Ready play,
准备，演奏，
one two,
1 2 ，
next line go,
下一行开始，
last line.
最后一行。
Very good, let's play one more time,
很好，让我们再弹一次，
this time we're gonna go quite a bit faster,
这一次我们会弹得更快，
sounds more like a song.
听起来更像一首歌。
Ready play,
准备，演奏，
next line.
下一行。
Very good,
非常好，
now if you want to play the chords along with that,
如果你想使用和弦一起演奏，
remember we have our C chord,
记得我们有 C 和弦，
we also have our G7 chord,
我们还有 G7 和弦，
so at this point, if you want to just play a strum for each note,
所以在这一点上，如果你只想为每个音符弹奏一段，
that's probably pretty good,
这可能是很好的，
not gonna talk about strumming patterns until a later time,
稍后再讨论弹奏模式，
but if you want to just the chords for that,
但如果你想只演奏和弦，
let's just do,
那就让我们这样做，
I guess we can try and do the whole thing,
我想我们可以试着做所有的事情，
let's try,
让我们试一下，
ready from the top, using the chords,
从顶部做好准备，使用和弦，
ready, go, two three four,
准备，开始， 2 3 4 ，
G7,
G7 ，
C,
C ，
next line,
下一行，
third line,
第三行，
just keep playing through these,
继续弹下去，
if it's an open measure,
如果是一个空小节，
you just keep playing through it
那就继续弹下去，
until the chord changes, now,
直到和弦改变，现在，
last line,
最后一行，
here's quick chord change.
这个和弦变化很快。
Very good, we have covered all kinds of things this session
非常好，我们覆盖了这节课上讲到的所有内容，
and I hope it's been enjoyable for you
我希望你过得愉快，
and we will see you next session.
我们下一节课再见。